Usama Sattar

Full Stack Developer

iamusamasattar@gmail.com | ♥ Rawalpindi, Pakistan | 🕻 +92 335 5347271 | 🖫 /usama-sattar

About Me

I am a full stack developer with 4+ years of experience in software development. I am always energetic and eager to learn new skills. I am an effective communicator with all levels of employees. Furthermore, I am extremely driven with clear goal to success.

Objective

To obtain a full time job working as a software engineer to develop, maintain and design software.

Education Islamabad, Pakistan

COMSATS University

BS(Computer Science) CGPA: 3.27/4

Skills

- HTML/CSS React/Next JS Node JS Express JS SQL/No SQL Git/GitHub React Native GraphQL
- Typescript Java PHP

Experience

Remotoco 04/2024 - Present

Full Stack Developer

- Developed Remotoco product from scratch, for a job matching platform.
- Collaborated with the product team to define features and refine product specifications.
- Presented product updates and progress to both the product and marketing teams, communicating technical details to non-technical stakeholders.

Genus Tech LLC 05/2022 - 04/2024

Full Stack Developer

- Developed multiple projects from scratch using JavaScript and MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js).
- Integrated conferencing tools, including Zoom, Google meet, and MS Teams.
- ImpleIented real time features like notifications using web sockets.
- Deployed applications on AWS, and Heroku, with CI/CD pipelines for automated deployment.
- · Facilitated developer meetings and conducted code reviews for improved code quality.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to define project goals.

Ninjas Code 01/2022 - 05/2022

Full Stack Developer

- Maintained web and mobile applications developed on MERN stack and GraphQL, using Expo CLI for mobile development.
- Managed the ongoing development and maintenance of a multivendor food delivery application, ensuring that it remained feature-rich, reliable, and up-to-date.
- Revamped and modernized both the mobile and web applications, significantly enhancing performance and user engagement.

Instasoft Solutions 09/2021 - 11/2021

Junior Software Engineer

- Assisted in developing dynamic web applications using PHP and MySQL.
- Worked on various Java programming tasks and contributed to the development of software applications.